ILGWU International Relations Department Records 5780/062
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU International Relations Department Records
1968-1998
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Mendelsund, Henoch
Briones, Michele
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/062
34.5 cubic feet
34.5 linear ft.
Articles, correspondence, photographs, records (documents).
The International Relations Department records consist chiefly of the correspondence of its director, Henoch Mendlesund, during his tenure from 1968-1980, and Michele Briones. The collection also includes articles, reports, conference materials, photographs, and other items. b The materials in this collection have an emphasis on labor issues in the developing world. There is correspondence with leaders of clothing and textile workers' unions in India, Japan, Turkey, Kenya, Latin America, Namibia, South Korea, among other countries. Other items concern conventions and conferences of the ILGWU that emphasized international issues, visits from foreign union leaders to the ILGWU, and visits of ILGWU leaders to foreign countries. There are also some materials about garment workers' unions in Western Europe. Topics addressed include working conditions, human rights, economic, political, and social conditions in developing countries, and requests for aid to assist foreign unions.
3781521
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
D. Mordente, October 14, 2008
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 10, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
The International Relations Department of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU) was concerned primarily with outreach to foreign and international labor organizations, working conditions in foreign countries, and international organizing activities. The department worked closely with international relations units of national and international labor confederations, such as the Free Trade Union Committee (FTUC) and the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU).
For more information about the ILGWU's involvement in international affairs, please visit:
http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/ILGWU/collectionGuides/internationalAffairs.html
Scope and Contents
The International Relations Department records (5780/062) consist chiefly of the correspondence of its director, Henoch Mendlesund, during his tenure from 1968-1980, and Michele Briones. The collection also includes articles, reports, conference materials, photographs, and other items. The materials in this collection have an emphasis on labor issues in the developing world. There is correspondence with leaders of clothing and textile workers' unions in India, Japan, Turkey, Kenya, Latin America, Namibia, South Korea, among other countries. Other items concern conventions and conferences of the ILGWU that emphasized international issues, visits from foreign union leaders to the ILGWU, and visits of ILGWU leaders to foreign countries. There are also some materials about garment workers' unions in Western Europe. Topics addressed include working conditions, human rights, economic, political, and social conditions in developing countries, and requests for aid to assist foreign unions. A collection of publications (5780/062 PUBS) consists of printed material either created or collected by the International Relations Department of the ILGWU.
Documentation of the ILGWU's influence and work in international relations is considerable and, though some of it may be found in the most obvious of placesthe David Dubinsky correspondence, the International Relations Department records, or the various editions of Justicesome of it may be found in everyday operational records of local unions and joint boards. These records not only illustrate the work that the ILGWU conducted independently and with the AFL and later the AFL-CIO; they also show the work of individual members and officers working with closely related organizations, such as the Jewish Labor Committee and the Italian-American Labor Council. Additionally, the work of the ILGWU and other unions in the United States is reflected in the records and collected documents of other organizations held at the Kheel Center. These include the papers of Serafino Romualdo, the collected documents of John P. Windmuller, and records of the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions and World Federation of Labor.
Individuals represented in the collection include Irving Brown, Sol Chaikin; Jay Lovestone, George Meany, Saby Nehama, Lazare Teper, and Charles S. Zimmerman. Organizations include the AFL- CIO and its International Affairs Dept.; Gewerkschaft Textil-Bekleidung; the Interamerican Textile, Leather and Garment Workers' Federation; the International Textile, Garment and Leather Workers' Federation and its Asian Regional Organization; the Korean National Textile Workers Union; the Namibian Trade Union Council; the South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO); the Tailors and Garment Workers Union (Great Britain); the Tailors and Textile Workers' Union (Kenya); the Textile, Knitting, and Clothing Workers Union of Turkey; the Textile Labour Association (India); the U.S. Dept. of Labor's Bureau of International Labor Affairs; and Zensen Domei (Japan).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/062 PUBS: ILGWU International Relations Department publications
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- India; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- Japan; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- Kenya; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- Turkey; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- Latin America; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- Korea (South); Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- Europe; Human rights -- Developing countries; International labor activities.; Labor unions -- Developing countries; Work environment -- Developing countries; Developing countries--Economic conditions.; Developing countries -- Social conditions; Developing countries -- Politics and government; Briones, Michele; Brown, Irving, 1911-; Chaikin, Sol C.; Lovestone, Jay.; Meany, George, 1894-1980; Mendelsund, Henoch.; Nehama, Saby.; Teper, Lazare, 1908-; Zimmerman, Charles S., 1896-1983.; AFL-CIO.; AFL-CIO. Dept. of International Affairs.; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; Federacion Interamericana de Trabajadores de la Industria Textil, Vestuario y Cuero.; Gewerkschaft Textil-Bekleidung.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. International Relations Dept.; International Textile, Garment and Leather Workers' Federation.; Korean National Textile Workers' Union.; Namibian Trade Union Council.; SWAPO.; Tailors' & Garment Workers' Trade Union.; Tailors and Textile Workers' Union (Kenya); Textile Labour Association (India); Textile Workers' Asian Regional Organization.; Turkiye Tekstil, Orme ve Giyim Sanayii I?scileri Sendikasi.; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees--Archives; United States. Bureau of International Labor Affairs.; Zensen Domei (Japan)
3781521
- A, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Amnesty International report on Argentina, 1978.
- African-American Labor Center, Washington D.C. [folder 1 of 5], 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Corres. re Maida Springer Kemp's trip to Africa, 1978; ILG contributions of office equipment and sewing machines to the Institute of Tailoring and Cutting, Kenya, 1978; ILG contributions of medical equipment to Mauritania and Mali, 1978.
- African-American Labor Center, Washington D.C. [folder 2 of 5], 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- African-American Labor Center, Washington D.C. [folder 3 of 5], 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- African-American Labor Center, Washington D.C. [folder 4 of 5], 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- African-American Labor Center, Washington D.C. [folder 5 of 5], 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Incl. correspondence. with (I.c.w.) Sol Stetin and Jack Sheinkman.
- AFL-CIO, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  I.c.w. George Meany.
- AFL-CIO International Affairs, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  I.c.w. Jay Lovestone, Ernest Lee and Michael Boggs.
- American Institute for Free Labor Development, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  I.c.w. Jesse Friedman.
- American-Asian Free Labor Institute [folder 1 of 2], 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  I.c.w. Morris Paladino re Textile Workers' Asian Regional Organization (TWARO).
- American-Asian Free Labor Institute [folder 2 of 2], 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- B, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  I.c.w. David Brombart and Karl Buschmann.
- Brown, Irving, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- D, 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- E, 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  I.c.w. Mostafa Ibrahim Mostafa, Gen. Trade Union for Hotel and Tourist Workers, re ILG's trip to Egypt.
- F, 1972-1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  I.c.w. Abraham Feinglass; and Free Trade Institute.
- Fashion Institute of Technology. Labor-Management Lecture Series., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- G, 1972-1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  I.c.w. Harvey Gold re German Leather Workers' Union visit to the U.S., 1979.
- Garment, Textile, Cordage and Allied Workers' of the Philippines (GATCORD), National Union of., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- (Tailors and) Garment Workers, National Union of., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Gewerkschaft Textile-Bekeidung, 1973-1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  I.c.w. Karl Buschmann, Pres., and Berthod Keller, Assist. to President.
- H, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- I, 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Incl. correspondence., reports from Italian labor, 1978-1980.
- InterAmerican Leather and Garment Federation (FITITVC), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  I.c.w. Carlos Bedoya.
- InterAmerican Textile, Leather and Garment Workers' Federation, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- International Labour Organization, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Corres., speeches re Geneva meeting.
- ILO, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- ILGWU, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  I.c.w. Sol C, Chaikin, Lazare Teper, Shelly Appleron, Jay Mazur and Ted Bernstein; notes re Dong-Il workers of South Korea, 1979.
- ILGWU, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- ILGWU, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- ILGWU Convention, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  International affairs report and resolutions.
- ILGWU Convention, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  International affairs report.
- ILGWU Convention, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Foreign visitors.
- ILGWU General Executive Board, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Resolutions submitted to AFL-CIO Convention 1975; International Relations Dept. report to GEB 1978.
- J, 1975-1980 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  I.c. re Japan Society.
- Joint Conference of ILGWU-ACTWU-Zensen, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Joint Conference of ILGWU-ACTWU-Zensen, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  I.c.w. Jacob Sheinkman and Tadanobu Usami; Conference statement.
- Joint Conference of ILGWU-ACTWU-Zensen, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Data for conference prepared by all three unions.
- Joint Conference of ILGWU-ACTWU-Zensen, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Nov. 14-15, 1977.
- Joint Conference of ILGWU-ACTWU-Zensen, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1a)
  Material prepared by all three. unions for conference.
- Joint Conference of ILGWU-ACTWU-Zensen, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1b)
  Prepared material translated into Japanese.
- Joint Conference of Textile and Apparel Workers Unions of Japan-USA, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  July 1-2, 1975.
- K, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Tailors' and Textile Workers' Union, Kenya, 1977.
- Korean National Textile Workers' Union, 1975-1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- L, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Includes Lovestone article on Iran.
- Labor, Department of, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  International Labor Affairs, Dept.
- Latin America, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Incl. report on mine-workers and human rights in Chile and Bolivia.
- M, 1975-1980 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  I.c.w. David Morse; and Ken Murray, Gen. Sec., Trade Union Conference (TUC).
- N-O, 1974-1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  I.c.w. Namibian Trade Union Council; Saby Nehama.
- P, 1975-1980 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  I.c. re Portugal; Mrs. Martin Plettl.
- Photographs (Box 5, Folder 1)
- R, 1974-1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  I.c. re Pier Luigi Romita of Italian Social Democratic Party visit to U.S.
- S, 1975-1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  I.c.w. Dtlef Servas; South-West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO-Democrats); Sol Stetin (TWUA).
- Spain, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  I.c.w. Solidaridad de Trabajadores Vascos; Damian Joya of Union General de Trabajadores (UGT).
- Spain, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Spain, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- State Department, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- T, 1973-1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  I.c.w. Lazare Teper.
- Tailors and Garment Workers Union, (British), 1977-1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Textile, Garment and Leather Workers' Federation, International (ITGLWF), 1973-1978 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- ITGLWF, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- ITGLWF, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- ITGLWF, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- ITGLWF, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- ITGLWF, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- ITGLWF, International Congress, Vienna. [folder 1 of 2], 1980 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- ITGLWF, International Congress, Vienna. [folder 2 of 2], 1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- ITGLWF, 2nd Congress, Dublin. [folder 1 of 2], 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  I.c.w. Irving Brown, reports and resolutions.
- ITGLWF, 2nd Congress, Dublin. [folder 2 of 2], 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  I.c.w. Irving Brown, reports & resolutions.
- ITGLWF, International Congress, Amsterdam, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- ITGLWF [folder 1 of 6], 1973-1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Include. Executive Committee and Presidium minutes and reports.
- ITGLWF [folder 2 of 6], 1973-1980 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- ITGLWF [folder 3 of 6], 1973-1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- ITGLWF [folder 4 of 6], 1973-1980 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- ITGLWF [folder 5 of 6], 1973-1980 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- ITGLWF [folder 6 of 6], 1973-1980 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- ITGLWF, 1972-1979 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- ITGLWF, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Textile, Knitting and Clothing Workers; Union of Turkey, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Textile Labor Assoc. (India), 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  I.c.w. A.N. Buch, President.
- Textile Workers' Asian Regional Organization [folder 1 of 4], 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Textile Workers' Asian Regional Organization [folder 2 of 4], 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Textile Workers' Asian Regional Organization [folder 3 of 4], 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Textile Workers' Asian Regional Organization [folder 4 of 4], 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- U-V-W, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- World Rehabilitation Fund, 1974-1978 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  I.c.w. Howard A. Rusk.
- X-Y-Z, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  I.c.w. Mrs. Maria Irene Salgado Zenha and Charles Zimmerman.
- YIVO Institute for Jewish Research, 1975-1979 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Zensen, 1975-1980 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  I.c.w. Tadanobu Usami, President.
- GEB, International Relations Department Report, 1993-1995 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- GEB, International Relations Department Report, 1990-1992 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- GEB, International Relations Department Report, 1986-1989 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- GEB, International Relations Department Report, 1980-1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- International Director's Meetings, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Memos to Jay Mazur, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Memos to Jay Mazur, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Memos to Jay Mazur, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Memos to Jay Mazur, 1986-1989 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Memos to Jay Mazur, 1986-1989 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Memos to Jay Mazur, 1986-1989 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Memos to ILGWU Staff, 1989-1994 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Memos to ILGWU Staff, 1989-1994 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Memos from Jay Mazur, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Memos from ILGWU Staff, 1990-1995 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Memos to Finance, 1982-1986 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Memos to Finance, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Memos to Finance, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Memos to Finance, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Memos to Finance, Michele Briones' expenses, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Memos to Finance, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Memos to Finance, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Memos to Finance, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Memos to Finance, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- International Account, 1989-1994 (Box 10, Folder 25)
- International Account, 1989-1994 (Box 10, Folder 26)
- International Account, 1989-1994 (Box 10, Folder 27)
- Finance check voucher forms, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Petty cash, Michelle Briones, 1991-1995 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Expenses, Michelle Briones, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Expenses, Michelle Briones, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Expenses, Michelle Briones, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Expenses, Michelle Briones, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Expenses, Michelle Briones, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Publication requests (other than subscriptions), 1992-1995 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Requests for information, 1986-1994 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Requests for information, 1986-1994 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Subscriptions, 1986-1989 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Subscriptions, 1990-1993 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Subscriptions, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Purchases, Union Label Department, 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Justice, 1981-1995 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Justice, 1981-1995 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Directories, 1981-1995 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Interpreters/Translators, 1991-1994 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Resumes, 1987-1995 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Speeches, studies, 1981-1994 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Speeches, studies, 1981-1994 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Bargaining, 1988-1991 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Bargaining, 1988-1991 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Bargaining, 1988-1991 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Biography (Box 11, Folder 25)
  no date
- CUNY-Center for Labor Management Policy Studies, 1989-1994 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Columbia University-Center for the Study of Human Rights, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- EPI, The State of Working America, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Economic Policy Institute (EPI), 1989 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- EPI, Policies of NAFTA, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- General Agreements on Tariffs and Trade (GATT) (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Histadrut, 1988-1994 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- International Labor Rights Education and Research Fund, 1990-1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- ILO, 1982-1995 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- ILO, 1982-1995 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- ILO, 1982-1995 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- ILGWU (Clippings), 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- International Rescue Committee (IRC) (Box 12, Folder 11)
- International Rescue Committee (IRC), 1990-1995 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- International Rescue Committee (IRC), 1990-1995 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Jewish Labor Committee, 1988-1994 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Norma Kamali, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- National Democratic Institute for International Affairs (Box 12, Folder 16)
- National Endowment for Democracy Conference, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- National Endowment for Democracy (Box 12, Folder 18)
- North American Agreement on Labor Cooperation (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Congress, NAFTA (Box 12, Folder 20)
- ILGWU, NAFTA Task Forces (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Labor Advisors Committee for Trade Negotiations, NAFTA Report, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 22)
- ORIT, 1986-1994 (Box 12, Folder 23)
- National Labor Committee, 1992-1995 (Box 12, Folder 24)
- ORT, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 25)
- Carl Pilgrim (Hubert Humphrey Fellow), 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 26)
- Socialist International and Socialist Democrats, 1988-1994 (Box 12, Folder 27)
- Socialist International and Socialist Democrats, 1998-1994 (Box 12, Folder 28)
- Stanley Foundation, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 29)
- U.S. Territories, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 30)
- Universal Declaration of Human Rights, 50th Anniversary (Box 12, Folder 31)
- AFL-CIO Convention, San Francisco, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- AFL-CIO Convention, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- AFL-CIO Convention, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- AFL-CIO Convention, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- AFL-CIO Convention, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- International Conference on Strategies for Global Labor Solidarity, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- International Conference on Strategies for Global Labor Solidarity, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- 42nd ILGWU Convention, international guests, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- 42nd ILGWU Convention, international guests, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- 42nd ILGWU Convention, international guests, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- 42nd ILGWU Convention, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- 42nd ILGWU Convention, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- 42nd ILGWU Convention, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- 41st ILGWU Convention, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- 41st ILGWU Convention, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- 41st ILGWU Convention, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- 41st ILGWU Convention, international relations booth, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- 40th ILGWU Convention, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- 40th ILGWU Convention, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Jordan/Israel, May, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- ILO Fourth Tripartite Technical Meeting for, the Clothing Industry, Geneva, February, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- ILO Fourth Tripartite Technical Meeting for, the Clothing Industry, Geneva, February, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Workshop in Burkina Faso, November, 1994; Fred Menuau,1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- DMC Meeting, Donna Burnett, France November, 1994, 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Connie September, New York, December, 1994, 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- FITTVCC Seminar, trade and workers' rights, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- ICFTV 6th World Women's Conference, The Hague, Lu Jinghus, October, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- ICFTV 6th World Women's Conference, The Hague, Lu Jinghus, October, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- ILGWU/ACTWU/FILTEA/UILTA Meeting, Florence, Italy, June, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- TEKSIF Women's Conference, Istanbul, Turkey, Gail Meyer, October, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Delegations to South Africa, support for national election, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Theo Steele and Edgar Blaavw (of SACTWU), visit to U.S., June, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- SACTWU National Congress, South Africa, Edgar Romney, July, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- ICFTU/ITS Mission to Thailand (Kader fire) Becky Plattus, November, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Bulgaria, Michelle Briones and Joe Danahy, June, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 16)